lincoln.ac.nz 2018-06-11

# Privacy | Lincoln University

_

The collection, use, storage, disclosure and correction of personal information by the University is governed by The Privacy Act 1993.

Personal information means information about an identifiable individual. The University complies with the obligations of this Act.

Lincoln University takes the privacy of those who use our service ("Users") very seriously. Please take a moment to read this Privacy Policy so you understand how we collect, store, use and share information. If you see anything that concerns you please email us at [web@lincoln.ac.nz](mailto:web@lincoln.ac.nz) as we may be able to clarify the need for it or work with you to alter it.

_

## Collection of information

_Automatically logged information  
_ The following information is recorded and logged by the University server when you visit this website:

  * Your browser's internet address
  * Your server's address
  * Your domain name
  * Your IP address
  * The date and time of your visit to the site
  * The pages you accessed and documents downloaded
  * The previous site visited
  * The type of browser you are using
  * The username entered if accessing a restricted site.

The University uses this information for statistical purposes and for system administration tasks to maintain this service. The University does not attempt to identify individuals as part of regular business practice. However, in the event of an investigation, the University, a law enforcement agency or other government agency may exercise its legal authority to inspect relevant server logs.

## Confidential and personal information

The University takes all reasonable precautions to guard against unauthorised access to confidential and personal information including the loss, misuse and alteration of the information held by the University on its servers. When personal information is no longer required for the purposes for which it was collected it may be deleted.

## Cookies and other tracking technologies for online services

 **Cookies and other tracking technologies for online services**  
This website collects statistical information which is used for making the site faster and easier to use. Your visit is anonymous – information from your visit is combined with the data from all site visitors and presented as statistical information on overall site use.

 Lincoln University does not collect personal identifiable information and does not facilitate the merging of any personally identifiable information with the non-personally identifiable information collected through any Google product or feature on this website. 

_The Lincoln University websites uses 'cookies' and other tracking technologies  
_

A 'cookie' is a file that our webserver may send to your computer when you access this website. This file is then stored on your computer. Lincoln University may use cookies and certain other passive information collection technologies to make your use of this website easier by allowing Lincoln University to provide better service, customise websites based on consumer preferences, compile statistics, analyse trends, and otherwise administer and improve this website. Certain features of the Lincoln University web site website may not work without use of passive information collection technologies.

 The Lincoln University web site uses 'session' cookies: Session cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your web browser window or otherwise turn your computer off. Session cookies are used, for example, to improve navigation on this site, and to collect aggregated statistical information.

Lincoln University may use 'persistent' cookies: Persistent cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of purposes, such as helping to determine what areas of the website visitors find most valuable, and customising the website based on your preferences on an ongoing basis. The Lincoln University server only knows that an unidentified visitor with your cookies has returned to the website and not any personally identifiable information.

 Lincoln University may use 'web beacons' (also known as internet tags, single-pixel GIFs, clear GIFs, anonymous identifiers and invisible GIFs): A web beacon is a tiny graphic on a web page or in an email message that is used to track pages viewed or messages opened. Web beacons tell the website server information such as the IP address and browser type related to the visitor’s computer. Web beacons may be placed on online advertisements that bring people to the Lincoln University web site and on different pages of the website. Web beacons provide us with information on how many times a page is opened and which information is consulted. Lincoln University uses both First Party and Third Party web beacons and cookies. Third Party web beacons and cookies are used for the purpose of marketing this website to people that may find benefit from the services included on the website. 

_Choices you have about Lincoln University’s use of cookies and other tracking technologies  
_

You can choose to enable or disable the use of cookies and other tracking technologies on this website. Cookies that are necessary to the operation of this website and for the provision of the services you have requested will continue to function regardless of whether you have provided consent. Other types of cookies and tracking technologies will be turned off until you provide explicit consent. As a result, the functionality of the Lincoln University website may be reduced until you choose to provide explicit consent.

 Some Internet browsers allow you to limit or disable the use of cookies and other tracking technologies. Please refer to the information provided by your Internet Browser for instructions on how to do so (generally found under a 'Help' menu).

 You can opt-out of any of the Google Analytics Advertising Features by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/> which is where users can download the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser Add-On. 

 You can also opt out by going to Google Ad Settings, which allows users to turn off the amount and type of data you are sharing. More information about opting out can be obtained from <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

## Use of personal information

Personal information you supply to us through the use of online forms, email, online surveys and feedback will be used for the purposes of the University including student administration matters, provision of services and the dissemination of information to staff, prospective and current students and remaining in contact with graduates.

## Disclosure of personal information

Personal information held by the University will only be disclosed to third parties with your consent unless the University is obliged to disclose information in certain circumstances set out in the Act or by order of any Court of Tribunal of competent jurisdiction.

If at any stage you provide us with your email address either as part of a message or by completing a web form, we will only use your email address for the purposes for which it was provided. We will not subscribe your email address to any external mailing list without your consent.

External sites that are linked to or from the University site are generally not under the control or responsibility of the University and you are advised to review their privacy statement.

## Data quality / access

The University will use reasonable endeavours to maintain accurate, up-to-date information regarding students and staff. If you believe that the personal information the University holds about you is inaccurate and requires correction or if you require copies of your personal information held by the University, please contact;

## Contact for more information

If you have questions or complaints about our privacy practices or procedures, please email us at [web@lincoln.ac.nz](mailto:web@lincoln.ac.nz) as we may be able to clarify the need for it or work with you to alter it. We will do our best to respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner.

_How will I know whether Lincoln University has updated this policy?  
_ Without prejudice to your rights under applicable law, Lincoln University reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy without prior notice to reflect technological advancements, legal and regulatory changes, and good business practices. Lincoln University may modify this Privacy Policy at any time and such modifications will be effective immediately on posting on the Lincoln University website.

## Privacy of Personal Information Students

Lincoln University will collect, use, store, and disclose personal information relating to students in accordance with the provisions of the Privacy Act 1993.

Where practicable all such personal information is obtained directly from students, or from their nominated agent(s). Additionally, information may be obtained or verified through relevant government or education agencies, including the New Zealand National Student Index.

Information will be stored on University files and database(s) and all reasonable security measures will be maintained. A unique identifier will be assigned to each student, which will be used in conjunction with a secondary means of identification or password/PIN.

Staff members and other personnel within the University or within agencies under contract to the University will have access to students’ personal information for purposes relevant to normal university operations including but not limited to: admission, enrolment, study, academic progress, tuition fees and charges, establishing and maintaining academic and graduation records, assessment, academic agreements (exchange/ study abroad partners, scholarship providers or sponsors, programme delivery partners), academic advice & support, student services, discipline, security and safety, Library and IT services, managing students’ association(s) membership and records, managing records of graduates, and other alumni, and managing and improving the quality of services provided by the University.

In order to conduct its proper business and as required under the Education Act 1989 and other laws, regulations, and contractual agreements by which it is bound, the University may use the student information it holds and may disclose information to external agencies such as government departments, bodies responsible for course moderation and professional accreditation or membership, agencies for financial support and pastoral care, and university student and alumni associations.10 Such agencies include, but are not limited to: 

• The Ministry of Education (information will be recorded on the National Student Index and used in an authorised information matching programme with the NZ Birth Register)   
• The Ministry of Social Development (including Work and Income NZ and StudyLink)   
• Inland Revenue Department  
• Te Puni Kōkiri    
• Immigration New Zealand (for students who are not NZ citizens)

• Relevant Professional bodies  
• Course moderation or accreditation bodies  
• Tertiary Education Commission  
• Ministry of Trade and Enterprise  
• Education New Zealand.

Information provided to external agencies is either student specific (typically name, date of birth, current contact details and academic/ graduation details) or cohort specific (aggregated or statistical information that does not identify individuals).21 Where provision or disclosure of information is voluntary or falls outside the scope of information the University is permitted to collect, store, use and disclose under the Privacy Act 1993, students will be advised and their consent will be obtained prior to the provision or disclosure of information.22 The University will make information held about students available to them upon request and in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993, which also describes the conditions under which information may be withheld. Students have the right to request correction of personal information held in accordance with the provisions of the Privacy Act 1993. If a student withholds information or provides incomplete, false or misleading information the University may decline or cancel the admission or enrolment and may withhold the academic record if its veracity cannot be confirmed.

This privacy statement operates in conjunction with any other [privacy statement](http://www.lincoln.ac.nz/footer/Privacy/).
